{Bold}A World That Defies Time

Little Planet; a tiny world filled with beauty and mystery.
Appearing over Never Lake for just one month a year, it is
a place where the past, present and future collide, thanks
to the mysterious Time Stones that lie hidden deep within
the planet.

Hoping to catch a glimpse of this cosmic event, Sonic
travels to Never Lake, followed by star-struck Amy Rose,
only to find the once-beautiful world chained and
imprisoned beneath a twisted metallic shell. The evil
genius Dr. Eggman has come for the Time Stones, and with
them may soon be able to command time itself!

Can Sonic stop Eggman and free Little Planet?

{Bold}Characters

SONIC THE HEDGEHOG
With a spirit like the wind, Sonic is the world's fastest
hedgehog who lives for adventure. Despite his carefree
attitude, he has a strong sense of justice and is always
ready to help those in need.
{-1:SonicAmy}





AMY ROSE
A bright and energetic girl who likes fortune telling and
mystic things. Amy is drawn to Little Planet after a
tarot card reading which tells of a destined encounter
with Sonic.





DR. EGGMAN (aka Dr. Ivo Robotnik)
With an IQ of 300 and a love of machines, Eggman dreams of
world conquest in order to create his own robotic utopia 
“Eggmanland”. He sees the Time Stones as the perfect tool 
for world conquest and will stop at nothing to get them.
{-1:Robo}





METAL SONIC
The ultimate robot doppelganger, Metal Sonic was built by
Eggman to rival Sonic’s power and speed in every way.
Programmed to follow Eggman's agenda, he’s out to cause
trouble for not only Sonic, but poor Amy too!



{Bold}Controls


{0,-18:Dpad}         1. Move Sonic with the directional buttons


{0,-18:DpadU}          2. Look Up


{0,-18:DpadD}          3. Look Down


{0,-10:But}         4. Jump / Spin Attack / Activate Flippers


{0,+6:start}         5. Pause the game


{Bold}Special Moves

ROLLING SPIN ATTACK
• Press the down directional button while moving to perform a 
  rolling spin attack.

SPIN DASH (Mega Drive/Genesis Mode)
• While standing still, touch and hold Down, then tap the Jump Button
to rev up like a turbo engine. 
• Keep tapping to increase the power of the Spin Dash
before releasing the directional button.

SPIN DASH (Original Mode)
• While standing still, touch and hold Down, then tap the Jump Button
  to rev up like a turbo engine.
• Maximum speed will be achieved when the Spin Dash is given
  time to charge before releasing the directional button.

SUPER PEEL OUT
• While standing still, touch and hold Up, then tap the Jump Button.
  Sonic’s feet will start racing at turbo speed.
• Release the directional button to blast off in a blaze of blue!
• Sonic is vulnerable to attack during a Super Peel Out.


{Bold}Essential Items

Collect rings to stay in the game.
If Sonic has at least one ring he won't lose a
life when he gets hit. Collect 100 rings to gain an additional life.

{-1:Ring}

Monitors contain various power-ups for Sonic:
Super Ring, Shield, Invincibility, Power Sneakers, and 1-Up.

{-1:Monitors}


A Lamp Post records your present score and time the moment
you touch it. If you lose a life in that Zone, you will start
your next Life at the last Lamp Post you touched.

{-1:Post}




{Bold}The Time Warp

Time Warp signs, marked Past and Future are scattered
around each Zone. When you hit one of these signs a Past
or Future symbol appears next to the Lives display. You can
now perform a Time Warp!

{-1:Future}





When you start moving fast enough, you’ll see bright stars
trailing behind Sonic. If you can keep up your speed for a
few seconds, the Time Warp will blaze into effect.

Sudden changes in speed, slowing down or coming within
range of the Goal will cancel the Time Warp. You can try
again as long you have a Past or Future symbol in your
possession.

You can use the Time Warp signs to travel between the
Past, Present and Future.  Since the Future isn’t yet
written, there are two different possibilities: a future where
Little Planet is free from Dr. Eggman’s control, or a future
where Eggman has wreaked havoc!

To ensure a good future for a Zone, you must either collect
all the Time Stones, or destroy Eggman’s robot transporter
contained within the Past.


{Bold}Special Stage

If you reach the Goal while carrying 50 rings or more, a
large golden Ring will appear at the end of the level. Jump
into it to enter the Special Stage.
The Special Stage is a 3D obstacle course scattered with
UFOs. If you can destroy all of the UFOs before the timer
runs out, you’ll pick up a Time Stone. Collect all seven
before Dr. Eggman finds them!

Each UFO conceals one of the following items:
• Power Sneakers give you an extra burst of speed
• Super Ring increases your ring count
• Time Bonus  adds 30 seconds to the timer

Some of the other items in the Special Stage will help you.
Others will make the course even more difficult! Watch out
for the water, it will shave 10 seconds off your timer.
